🛮 (+44) 7568 734 747 | 🗷 prannvat2005@gmail.com | 🏕 https://prannvat.github.io/Prannvat-Portfolio/ | 🖸 prannvat | 🛅 prannvat

## Summary\_

Proficient skills in several programming languages, and a strong determination to learn more, as well as adapt to new tasks and skills. I have experience in working in high-pressure environments and always maintain a healthy work environment.

### **Education**

Maiden Erlegh School Reading, Ut

A LEVELS

• 3 A's in Mathematics, Computer Science and Physics & a B in Further Mathematics

Maiden Erlegh School Reading, UK

**GCSEs** 

3 grade 9s, 4 grade 8's, 2 grade 7's, 1 grade 6

# Work Experience

FoodCLUB London, Ut

IOS Developer Sep. 2023 - PRESENT

- Integral part of the iOS development team for the FoodCLUB app.
- Using Swift and SwiftUI as well as Javascript to develop the revolutionary app for the future of the food tech industry.
- Working with complex libraries such as AVFoundation, to create intricate features.
- Work in a team of approximately 40 people and using GitHub and industry level work methodologies and architectures like MVVM.

#### Polkadot & Astar & Easy A

London, UK

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & PRODUCT FOUNDER

June. 2023

- Founded product that would regulate AI training data and ensure legitimacy of AI using Polkadot & Astar blockchain technology.
- Used Rust to implement smart contract on blockchain.
- Placed top 10 in international Hackathon.
- Organiser & Co-director of participating team.

Immutable X & Easy A London, UK

GAME DEVELOPER & PRODUCT DESIGNER

Feb. 2023

- Lead software developer in team of 5.
- Developed a working web3 train simulator game using **C#** on **Unity** using **Blender** to simulate a map of London.
- Used XCode to build an AR app which would show minted NFT'S from the game.
- Deployed smart contract on Immutable X NFT gallery using Typescript.
- · Lead presenter of product at international Hackathon.
- Organiser & Co-director of participating team.

Maiden Erlegh School Reading, UK

PRESENTER FOR < COMPUTER SCIENCE A LEVELS>

Dec. 2022

- Introduced the subject of computer science to secondary school students. Talked about the various fields in computer science and my experiences.
- Introduced my **machine learning** project that predicts the perfomances of Premier League footballers every week. Showed the different libraries, and ideas I used to implement my **neural network** and software using **Python**.
- Taught the basics of data science as well as showing students my work on data handling using SQL and Python Pandas.

FOUNDER OF TEZTOURNAMENTS

Dec. 2022

• Explained and designed a digital escrow system using the Tezos blockchain.

- Talked about designing and implementing such product in real life with a proof of concept and discussed the potential of the idea.
- Wrote the whitepaper, as well as code, in order to explicitly explain the product.
- https://github.com/subeenregmi/tez-tournaments

Tezos & Easy A. London, UK

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER & PRODUCT DESIGNER

Tezas

Nov. 2022

- Implemented web3 smart contract using SmartPy and Python.
- Designed and developed a beta for a decentralised social media platform, based on the Tezos **blockchain**.
- · Led team of 5 in creating and presenting this product and winning first place in international Hackathon.
- Organiser & Co-director of participating team.

January 5, 2024 Prannvat Singh · Résumé

JP Morgan Chase & Co. Reading, UK

**DATA ANALYST** Sep. 2022 - Oct. 2022

- Data Visualisation & Software development virtual experience.
- Ran tasks in order to analyse stocks of JP Morgan Chase & Co. using JavaScript and Python.

# **Projects**

Prannvat's Portfolio Githul

Creator Jan. 2024

- · Developed a functional, responsive website to share my portfolio, to allow me to connect, and network with people in the industry.
- Demonstrated understanding of HTML, CSS and JavaScript and showing my full-stack development skills.
- https://prannvat.github.io/Prannvat-Portfolio/

Nirmolak Heera Githui

Co-Creator Dec. 2023

- Developing a SwiftUI app to enable Sikh's to access, use and read their holy scripture the Guru Granth Sahib in a revolutionary way, allowing
  for easy, user-friendly use.
- · Using SwiftUI as well as UIKit in parts of the app and having the Combine framework in use for the MVVM articheture.
- Using **SQL** to manipulate, use, and access large amounts of data.

FPL Points Predictor Githut

CREATOR May. 2023

- Created and explained machine learning Python project, applicable for real-life use.
- Showed and explained **AGILE methodologies** used in the making of the project
- Demonstrated data science skills and managed massive amounts of data using API's, SQL and Pandas
- https://github.com/prannvat/fpl-points-predictor/blob/main/FPL\_Points\_Predictor\_Paper.pdf
- https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7ty3eTo4Quc&t=4s

THURSDAY - AI Chatbot Github

Creator Sep. 2023

- Developing an AI chatbot that uses speech recognition.
- Used Python skills as well as Natural Language Processing knowledge to develop chatbot.
- https://github.com/prannvat/AI-Chatbot

### **Extracurricular Skills**

Coding Society Reading, UK

Organiser & Mentor Dec. 2021 - Jul. 2022

- Taught aspiring software developers the basics of Python, logical thinking and hardware.
- Introduced concepts of Object Oriented Programming to beginners.

First Days Reading, UK

Charity Work Apr. 2022

• Ran a 5K and raised money for a children's charity

#### **Software Developing**

PROGRAMMING

- Python, C#, Visual Basic, JavaScript, Rust, HTML, SQL, Swift.
- $•\ \texttt{https://www.udemy.com/course/rust-programming-master-class-from-beginner-to-expert/programming-master-programming-programming-master-programming-master-programming-programming-p$
- https://www.udemy.com/course/swiftui-masterclass-course-ios-development-with-swift/

#### **Multi-Lingual**

FLUENT IN SEVERAL LANGUAGES

· English, Punjabi, Hindi, Urdu

### **Awards**

### INTERNATIONAL

2023 **Finalist**, Easy A & Immutable X International Hackathon London, Ut

2023 **Finalist**, Easy A & Polkadot & Astar International Hackathon London, U

2022 Winner, Easy A & Tezos International Hackathon London, UK

January 5, 2024 Prannvat Singh · Résumé 2